So, you're at GW University from 82 to
86, a boy from Pennsylvania,
and Middle Eastern studies is your
thing, and one day a professor pulls you
aside and makes an extraordinary
admission and offer to you. Tell us.
>> Right. I I got a degree in Middle
Eastern studies at George Washington
University. And to tell you the truth, I
wasn't ready to go into real life yet.
So, I stayed for a master's degree in
legislative affairs with a focus being
on American foreign policy analysis.
And I was taking a class called the
psychology of leadership with Dr.
Jerrold Post, who was an eminent
psychiatrist.
He gave us an assignment, quite a
controversial assignment, to shadow our
bosses, and then to write a
psychological profile of our bosses. I
did that.
And
it was a
I worked for a I worked for a sociopath.
And I called him on it.
And so, I got my paper back at the end
of the week, and I got an A, and Dr.
Post wrote in the margin, "Please see me
after class."
So, I went to his office to see him. He
had me close the door, and then he said,
"Look, I'm not really a professor here.
I'm a CIA officer undercover as a
professor here. I'm looking for people
who might fit into the CIA's culture,
and I think you would fit into the CIA's
culture. Would you like to be a CIA
officer?" And the truth is, you know, I
wanted to go into public service. I
wanted to see the world. But the real
truth was, I was getting married in 6
weeks, and I didn't have a job.
So, I said, "Yeah, sure. I'd love to
join the CIA." And the next thing I
knew, I was in the CIA.
>> So, what was it about you? Just your
ability to profile people?
>> That was the start of it, yes. It turned
out that I was hired by the office that
he had created about 6 years earlier,
called the political psychology
division. So, I was assigned to Iraq. I
became Saddam Hussein's classified
biographer,
and I did that for years before making a
what at the time was a very unusual
switch to counterterrorism operations.
But, the agency gave me opportunity
after opportunity. I learned to speak
fluent Arabic. That went with the fluent
Greek that I had. And um
Yeah, I mean, one day you're sitting in
a college class and the next day you're
in the Oval Office trying to think of,
you know, how not to sound like an idiot
when you're speaking to the president.
And yeah, the rest of the rest was
history.
>> And so, do you do you are you Was this
the kind of hire that you could tell
anybody about? Or like when you joined
the CIA? Or did they say, "No, your
cover's going to be you too are a
university professor."
>> Well, at the beginning, I was an overt
employee. So, I wasn't under formal
cover. But, what that meant
for all intents and purposes was that I
could tell those closest to me that I
was working for the CIA. And then that
was it. I mean, even my own wife, she
knew that I was a CIA officer. She had
no idea what I did.
That which caused all kinds of problems
later. And frankly, it led to our
divorce.
You know, you come home
and you say, she says, "How was your
day?" You say, "Great." "What did you
do?" "Nothing." "Who did you talk to?"
"Nobody." And then your phone rings at
11:00 and you say, you know, "The rain
in Spain falls mainly in the plain." And
then you leave until 6:00 in the
morning.
And that's just not conducive to a
to a a smooth marriage.
>> A healthy marriage. Did you really use
little phrases like that? Like the
pearls in the river?
>> Uh sometimes, yeah. Uh sometimes, if
you're not
close to the person that you're trying
to trigger an emergency meeting with, it
would be easy to say, "Hey, Constantine,
let's have coffee. I'll meet you
tomorrow morning at 9:00." Well,
tomorrow morning at 9:00 really means
tomorrow morning at 8:00 in the
abandoned, you know, parking lot behind
the sweater factory because you've
arranged that all in advance. So, if
somebody's listening to your phone, and
nowadays everybody's listening to your
phone, they don't have any idea what
you're going to do.
>> Well, I was interested in your I want to
get to all that, but I do I am
interested in your relationship with
your wife. You you've had two wives as I
understand it. And I heard you tell the
story in part, and I wanted to hear the
rest of it. So, you're in Greece.
>> Mhm.
>> And I think this is the first wife.
>> Right. My first wife.
>> son
your son said something shocking to you.
Can you tell us that story?
>> Yeah.
I was so focused on the job and and
trying not to get killed. You know,
there was a there was a terrorist group
active in Greece at the time called
Revolutionary Organization 17 November.
That was the whole reason why I was in
Greece at the at the in the
at the basis of it at all.
Uh it was to to try to infiltrate this
group to disrupt their attacks and
really to destroy the group from the
inside. They'd killed the CIA station
chief, two US defense attachés, the
Turkish ambassador, the deputy
ambassador, the minister of finance.
They they just killed they killed 28
people.
And so
she was uh a first generation American.
Her parents were were from Greece, and
she inherited her grandmother's house on
on one of the Greek islands. And so, she
started going to the island on the
weekends and taking the kids. I thought
that was a great idea. The kids can get
to know their cousins. Well,
leaving Friday, coming back Sunday
became leaving Thursday, coming back
Sunday, then leaving Thursday, coming
back Monday. The kids are missing
school. And then one day, I'm shaving,
getting ready for for work, and my then
6-year-old is sitting on the floor next
to me, and we're talking about his day
and what his day is going to look like.
And then he said to me, "I told Mommy
not to kiss Uncle Stelios on the lips. I
told her to kiss only you on the lips,
and she told me to mind my own
business."
I felt like I had been electrocuted.
And so I went into the bedroom and I
kicked the bed.
She said, "What?"
I said, "Who is Stelios?"
And she said, "Where did you hear that
name?" I said, "Who is he?"
And she said, "Don't believe everything
a 6-year-old says."
And I I said to her, and I said it very
plainly and clearly at the time, "I'm
going to leave right now before I do
something that's going to that's going
to dog me for the rest of my life."
And so I didn't even finish shaving. I
finished shaving at work. I got in the
car and I drove to the embassy, and it
was all downhill from there. As it
turned out, 17 November murdered the
British defense attaché a few months
later, Steven Saunders. Steven was a
friend of mine. We were next-door
neighbors.
And um
And a couple of months later they mailed
a manifesto to a leftist newspaper, and
they said in the manifesto, "Eda meton
megalo kataskopos, we saw the big spy,
but we knew that he was armed and he was
driving an armored car, so we elected to
carry out the revolutionary sentence on
the war criminal Saunders." Well, I got
to the office and the and the chief said
he came just barging into my office. He
said, "Did you see the manifesto?" I
said, "What manifesto?" He said, "The
Saunders manifesto." I said, "They
didn't leave a Saunders manifesto." He
said, "No, they released it today, and
you're in it." I said, "What do you mean
I'm in it?"
He said, "They set out to kill you that
morning."
And I said, "Oh my god." He said, "You
have to go." I said, "Go where?" He
said, "Home, like to Washington." I
said, "I just dropped my kids off at
school. I can't just up and go home." He
said, "Listen, you get in an armored
car, we're taking you to the airport.
We're going to pick up your kids, we're
going to pick up your wife. So, we all
met up at the airport.
And I said to her, I am so sorry.
And she said, I want a divorce. I'm not
living like this anymore.
And so, the plane landed in New York. I
caught a connection to Washington. She
caught a connection to Cleveland.
And that was the end of it.
>> Was that the end of it for Stelios, too?
>> Yeah.
Yeah, I uh
>> They didn't wind up together.
>> Oh, no. That guy could barely read. That
was uh no. She was feeling lonely, and
it was because I was so focused on the
job.
>> It was very hard to maintain a marriage
in the CIA.
>> so. Very, very much so. And you know,
I'll tell you another thing. Um
2 years later, I I was in Pakistan, and
I'm dating a CIA officer.
And uh
in Pakistan, we had this trunk line. So,
it was a just a normal phone, but it was
a 202 area code. So, it's it's like
you're making a local call. So, I think
we were like 11 hours ahead of
Washington, or 10 and 1/2 hours ahead of
Washington. So, I would call her uh
every morning when I got to the to the
office, because it was already evening
the previous day for her. And one of the
guys in my branch, um it they were all
retirees in my branch. They were all
either former chief or deputy chief of
Near Eastern um operations.
And um
And so, one of them heard me say,
Okay, I love you. Mwah. And I hung up
the phone. And he said, So, are there
wedding bells in the future? And I said,
Uh I don't know. I just got divorced,
and I really don't want to be a two-time
loser. And he says, Two-time loser? He
says, I've been married four times. Jim,
how many times have you been married?
Jim says, Five for me. Bill, how many
times have you been married? He says, I
have four. Dave, Dave has three. He
says, Two-time loser. Welcome to the
CIA, kid.
>> Wow.
I mean, I guess I'm not surprised. It
doesn't really breed intimacy.
>> Or honesty.
>> to mention your psychological profiling
skills, which if used against the wrong
person could be an annoyance to a
spouse.
>> But it's something you're really good
at.
>> when you're you know, you're going to do
a day trip or something or take your
kids to the you know, Luna Park or
whatever and you're taking some crazy
way. She says, "Where are you going?"
And the answer is, "Well, I don't want
anybody to shoot us on the way there."
And that's like a legitimate fear.
>> Thanks for watching this clip. If you're
new here, subscribe. We got a whole lot
more goodness where that came from.
Would love to hear your feedback. You
can email me, too.
megan.megyn@megynkelly.com
or just leave a comment below. But join
the community by becoming a subscriber.
We really, really value your input and
your support. We may not always agree,
but we are always going to talk about it
and respect. No BS, no agenda, no fear.
Think about this. In 2006, $20,000
equaled roughly 33 oz of gold at spot
price. At today's prices, those 33 oz
would be worth about $165,000.
That's why many smart Americans
diversify a portion of their savings
into precious metals. And that's why you
should consider buying gold from Birch
Gold Group. For thousands of years, gold
has been a store of wealth. And today
it's a crucial part of any balanced
strategy. Even better, Birch Gold can
help you convert an existing IRA or 401k
into a tax-sheltered retirement account
in gold. Just text MK to the number
989898 to receive your free info kit on
gold. There's no obligation, just useful
information. With an A+ rating with the
Better Business Bureau and tens of
thousands of happy customers, let Birch
Gold help you diversify with gold. Now,
that's peace of mind. Again, text MK to
today.